Job Offers}
Hanato Kobato, Private Eye}
Bye-bye!
Bye-bye, Kobato-chan!
Okay, see you on Monday!
I’m sorry!
Every single time…
Are you all right?
It’s fine, move it! I’m late.
Are you working again?
Yeah.
Ah, Kobato-chan!
Good job today!
Um, is there anything you need help with?
I’m all right. You can go home.
Wow…
There are this many jobs available?
What are you doing borrowing that booklet?
I’m going to work, of course! Just like Fujimoto-san!
So you are going to help pay
off at least some of the debt?
Yes!
I’ll invigorate myself delivering papers in the morning.
You, who sleeps late every day?
Okay, then…
I’ll deliver pizza to peoples’ houses!
You’ll get lost for sure!
Th-Then…
I’ll help the professional movers.
You’d screw that up by
breaking vases and stuff.
Then what kind of work can I do?
Don’t ask me!
That’s it! I’m through!
Ioryogi-san…
Hello!
Coming!
Oh!
He’s torn!
Poor thing.
Thank you.
It’s no problem.
Here, all done.
Thank you very much!
You’re welcome.
Oh, I have one more thing to ask you.
Hmm?
Oh! You’re the one who gave me the umbrella!
Oh, I know you!
Thank you for your help that day!
You’re welcome.
Oh my, you two already know each other?
Yes. Once again, I’m Ueda, the shop owner.
I’m Hanato Kobato!
Kobato-san lives in our apartment and
normally helps out at Yomogi Preschool.
Right now she’s looking for a place to work, so I thought of this shop!
Is that right?
If you can give us a hand on the weekends when we’re busy, that would be great.
At least until my hands heal up.
They’re this bad.
Whatever happened to you?
Well, sometimes I can get really clumsy.
It looks like she injured herself the other day.
Are you all right?
Yeah. But this puts my boss in a bind when we’re busy.
So I’m counting on you, Kobato-san.
Yes! I look forward to working here, boss!
And... um…
My name is Oumura Yumi.
Nice to have you, Kobato-chan.
All right, good luck, Kobato-san!
Yes!
I’ve changed!
Thank goodness! The uniform fits perfectly!
Now, what would you have me do?
Well… first you say “welcome” to any customers that come in.
Welcome!
J-Just like that.
Yes!
Then, when you hear their orders,
you put the cakes in those boxes.
You mean these?
I will open up the register and take their payment…
“Thank you very much!” Right?
That’s right!
Welcome!
Well, let’s see how it goes.
Yes!
Let’s see… shortcake and…
a Mont Blanc. Then I’ll have…
Shortcake… a Mont Blanc…
The cheesecake… no the apple pie.
Cheesecake… apple pie…
Then I’ll have the lemon tart.
Lemon…? Um…
I’ll also have the chou à la crème too.
Uh… um…
Shortcake, a Mont Blanc, apple pie, a lemon tart and a chou à la crème.
That’s amazing, Yumi-san!
Kobato-chan, can you put them in a box?
Y-Yes!
Let’s see, shortcake and…
Ah! I’m sorry!
Calm down, just get another one.
O-Okay.
Kobato-chan, are you all right?
Y-Yes!
Now we need the Mont Blanc and…
…apple pie, lemon tart and chou à la crème.
All done!
Now for the finishing touch.
Thank you very much!
Thank you, you perky clerk.
Did I do well?
Yeah! You’ll be fine once you get the hang of it.
Welcome!
Huh?
Kobato-chan!
Marina-chan and her mother! Welcome!
Why hello!
So you’re a cake-shop keeper, Kobato-chan?
Yes! Today I’m a cake-shop keeper!
Lucky!
What kind of cake do you want?
Today we’re getting my birthday cake!
Ah, it’s your birthday?! Congratulations!
Kobato-chan, could you package it?
Yes!
If you please.
Here.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Thank you, Kobato-chan!
Thank you very much!
Bye!
Huh?
What’s wrong?
I wonder how this happened?
We must have given her the wrong cake.
I’ll go after Marina-chan!
Marina-chan!
Kobato-chan, are you okay?
Y-Yes…
Welcome!
I’ll have this and this.
Yes!
Kobato-chan, this customer had the Mont Blanc and cheesecake.
Ah! I’m sorry!
I’m tired.
Kobato-chan, good job today.
Ah, good job today!
Here, you can have this.
Thank you very much!
Ioryogi-san will be pleased!
Io…
He’s a stuffed animal in public.
Huh?
I look forward to seeing you tomorrow.
Do you mean it? I can come back tomorrow?
Yes, of course!
You can go home too, Yumi-chan.
Uh, but what about the clean-up?
I’ll take care of that.
And you still haven't healed.
Let's not overdo it.
Okay.
Okay, boss, I’m leav-
I’m leaving now!
All right, good job today.
Is something the matter?
Huh? No no.
Nothing at all.
But Yumi-san, you seem
preoccupied about something.
I’m just worried about my boss.
Our boss?
He seems troubled by something.
I tried asking him once,
but he just said it was nothing.
Is that true?
The shop is doing well too.
Then I wonder what exactly is troubling our boss?
He’s probably in debt!
Huh?
Yomogi Preschool is in a lot of trouble over that.
Kobato-chan, are you working for us because of that?
Yes!
How admirable…
Oh, Sayaka-sensei and Fujimoto-san are much more admirable than I am.
That's why I have to help them out, even if it isn’t much!
I also want to help my boss.
This is really good!
Not being able to help someone even though you want to must be hard.
I will investigate what is troubling our boss!
Well, that’s good and all, but step out of bounds and you’ll get fired.
Then I won’t be able to eat
any more of these tasty cakes!
But then, there are a whole lot of other places you could work at.
Sushi bars!
Steak houses!
Chinese gourmet places!
Kobato, what job are you planning on next?
I’m still going to work at the cake shop!
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato-chan!
Could you line up these cookies on the shelf.
Yes!
Well, I’ll leave it to you.
Did he just look at me and sigh?
Huh? Did he?
I wonder why?
Is the boss troubled… over me?
I will go ask our boss what is troubling him!
Huh?
Let me handle it!
Really? Then, could you do it casually?
Yes. I will do my best!
Um…
Kobato-san?
Yes. Um… actually…
Actually, I want to ask you something nonchalantly!
Kobato-chan…!
What is it?
There must be something troubling you, am I right?
Don’t you worry. There’s nothing troubling me.
But…
Yumi-san told me that sometimes you’re lost in thought, that you want to say something.
That it’s so strange.
There is nothing for
Yumi-chan to be worried about.
That’s what he said!
If that’s what he told you, then I
guess I was worrying over nothing.
Welcome!
Oh?
Kobato-chan?
Sayaka-sensei!
Why are you here?
She’s here to help out until I’m healed.
Is that true?
Are you here to get a cake?
I’m going to go visit Chitose.
I thought I’d buy her a treat.
It’s been a while since I had a Chiroru cake.
I’m pretty sure I took your order
for your husband’s birthday cake.
Uh, yeah.
Sayaka-sensei’s husband…
That would mean she got married.
But I’ve never seen him for myself.
Then that means they’ve split up.
Sayaka-sensei seemed so sad.
Don’t ask her point-blank about that.
But why not?
She probably doesn’t want to talk about that.
Even you aren’t saying that you’re
working for Yomogi Preschool’s sake.
Nobody spills the beans
about absolutely everything.
Our boss at Chiroru must be just like that.
But Yumi-san wants to know.
What am I supposed to do then?
Then you investigate more sneakily.
Although I don’t think you’re up to the job, Dobato.
But, I’ll do my best!
Thank you very much!
Well, you are pretty sneaky.
Ah, it’s Kobato-san!
What are you doing?
I’m investigating sneakily.
Wow, cool!
Just like a detective!
Detective?
So that’s a detective?
Yeah!
Yup!
He investigates a whole lot!
Motives, alibis, evidence…
Then there are inquests,
gathering info, and trailing suspects!
Sounds awesome!
The two of us will help you!
No! Detectives work alone!
Really?
Looks like she’s rushing
down the wrong path again.
Thank you very much!
Um, excuse me!
Today, I am a detective.
Eh? Detective?
Did you notice anything strange about Chiroru?
No, not at all.
Did something happen there?
Yes!
It’s the case of what’s
troubling the shopkeeper!
The shopkeeper?
Is troubled?
Do you have any ideas?
No, even if we ask him…
Anything at all?
Chiroru cakes are popular, so it can’t be about work…
Is that so?
Thank you very much!
W-Well, if you’ll excuse us…
This is beyond maddening!
I’ll just use my own dragnet.
Dragnet?
What?!
You think I’ll take you up on that?
You’re sure stingy, Genko.
Only when discussing romance! Hit me with something else!
Well, I guess I’ll take my souvenir and my leave.
Hey! You just came here to eat my Baumkuchen, didn’t you!
You didn’t know already?
What?!
Adios!
Good night!
Yumi-san!
Kobato-chan?
Good evening!
What are you doing?
I’m a detective!
Right now I've gathered that Chiroru cakes are popular, and that his troubles aren’t about his job.
But he’s always giving…
…chocolates as gifts to small kids.
He’s always wondering about people’s health.
And I understand that everybody loves the cakes our boss makes.
And I even received some chocolates!
Our boss is so nice to everyone.
Yumi-san, let’s follow him!
Kobato-chan, it’s fine. Can we go?
But…
Huh?
He looks like he’s waiting for someone.
We can’t keep following him anymore. But still…
Someone’s coming!
I wonder who she is?
You don’t know?
Not a clue.
Could it be a date?
So that’s why he won’t talk to me about it!
What should I do, Kobato-chan?
Please calm down, Yumi-san!
Our boss will notice us!
Yumi-chan?
Yumi-san?!
Yumi-san!
Wait!
Boss-
Kobato-chan?
Owweee…
Are you all right?
I’m fine!
In any case, who were you meeting, boss?
Actually, it’s an interview.
For a new part-timer.
A part-timer? Why?
Because I haven’t been giving
you breaks on weekends, Yumi,
despite Kobato-san coming to help.
Breaks?
I thought you might be worn out. And I
think you injured yourself because of that.
Boss…
So you were worried about that?
Yes.
You’ve been working very hard, and I took it for granted. I’m very sorry.
Don’t be.
I enjoy working with you.
You don’t have to give me time off.
I find pleasure in connecting with the customers who appreciate your cakes.
And I like seeing you every day!
And... about my injuries…
Well…
It’s very cute!
Yumi-chan, did you…?
Yes.
I injured myself so many times because I was practicing how to make cakes.
I wanted to be of more help to
you, boss, so I’ve been studying…
I’m sorry for keeping this from you.
Can I try it?
Y-Yes.
It’s delicious.
Really?
The new part-timer will be starting soon,
and we’ll have more time for me
to teach you how to make cakes.
Okay!
Oh, so you solved the case, huh?
Yes! Detective Kobato
has closed another case!
Her boss was able to give Yumi-san her time off.
And Yumi-san is able to
help her boss even more.
The two were considerate of each other’s feelings… it was a very wonderful case!
Well, great to hear.
And I get to eat another Baumkuchen.
That Baumkuchen isn’t from Chiroru.
And you have brought back this type of treat before…
I wonder if this has anything to do with your dragnets?
Oh, right!
This time you get…
100 sweet points, because I got to eat cake!
Really?!
Fujimoto-san!
What is it?
I have something for you!
It’s chocolate I got from my work!
Work? You?
I’m also working very hard!
So you should take some time off and go to your university, Fujimoto-san!
Well, I don’t see a lot of good
coming out of you “working hard.”
You’re mean.
Hey.
Don’t work yourself to death.
Does that mean you’re worried about me?
No, I’m not.
Thank you very much!
Anyways, do something about that scribble on your face.
This is 100 points!
What are you talking about? They’re scribbles, right?
They are not!
Since you’re such a meanie,
Fujimoto-san, you get 50 points!
I don’t get you.